Dave Hubertus

Software Developer | Former Chemist

SUMMARY

I am a skillful Software Developer with a persistent craving to learn. From my professional experience as Developer and Chemist, I have developed a passion for innovation, design, problem solving, and data analytics. My skill set is currently rooted in JavaScript environments, and I use the fundamentals I have developed to quickly learn new languages and frameworks. I value collaboration, agile processes, and strongly believe purpose is key to one's success.

EXPERIENCE

Digital Data Services, Denver, CO — Application Developer

SEPTEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

Digital Data Services is a consultancy that provides custom, desktop and mobile, geospatial web mapping solutions. Utilizing React, Node, Django, PostgreSQL, and various other languages, libraries, and frameworks, I customize web applications by designing and building out new features to increase functionality and overall ease of use.

Turing School of Software and Design, Denver, CO

JANUARY 2017 - AUGUST 2017

Turing students invest over 1,500 hours across seven months in becoming job-ready software developers. In the Front End Engineering program we begin by building skills in HTML, CSS, and Design Fundamentals. We continue by laying a solid foundation in core JavaScript, then progress into React. In the final quarter, students build backend applications with Node and SQL. In total, FEE graduates have the skills to turn design comps into working applications.

Ciris Energy Inc, Centennial, CO — Process Chemist

MARCH 2014 - DECEMBER 2016

R&D through commercialization of a green chemistry process involving the conversion of biomass waste streams into relevant and lucrative chemicals.

Bedoukian Research Inc, Danbury, CT — Synthetic Chemist

SEPTEMBER 2011 - OCTOBER 2013

 $Large-scale\ organic\ synthesis\ and\ distillation\ of\ fragrances,\ flavorings,\ and\ insect\ pheromones.$

EDUCATION

Keene State College, Keene, NH

BS Chemistry / BA Secondary Education

08/2006 - 12/2010

(203) 241-1899

davehubertus@gmail.com

in: dave-hubertus-04128327

git: dhubertus

personal site:

www.davehubertus.com

SKILLS

HTML / CSS / Sass

JavaScript / jQuery / TypeScript

React / Redux

Python / Django

Google Maps / Leaflet / Mapbox

Node / Express

SQL / ORM's / Knex / Sequelize

PostgreSQL / SQLite

AWS / API Gateway / Lambda / S3 / Beanstalk

Create & Consume RESTful / SOAP APIs

Local Storage / JSON Web Token / WebSockets

TDD / Mocha / Chai / Enzyme

Webpack

Data Analytics / Visualization

Git / Github / CI Front End Build Pipelines

Photoshop / GIMP

Design Fundamentals

PROJECTS

UFO Sightings

GitHub

 $\underline{https://github.com/dhubertus/ufo-sighting-google-maps}$

Using React, Router, Google Maps API, and The National UFO Reporting API the user can research UFO sightings dating back to the 1950s.

MovieTracker

GitHub:

https://github.com/dhubertus/MovieTracker

Using Redux, React, and PostgreSQL a user can perform all basic functionality of an online streaming site from creating a user account to favoriting movies.